Guide to the Alfred Stephen McCarthy Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Alfred Stephen McCarthy papers
1877-1955
1901-1941
MS 1856
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
The papers consist of a diary kept by McCarthy during his year of service with the 6th Imperial Bushmen cavalry unit in the Boer War, 1900-1901; legal documents, including birth and marriage certificates; limited correspondence; photographs; records kept by McCarthy during his tenure as a sergeant with the New South Wales police, 1901-1922; a collection of McCarthy's bush poetry; and newspaper clippings collected by McCarthy.
McCarthy, Alfred Stephen, 1878-1955
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator, 2005.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Arrangement
Inventory, 1877-1955
Scope and Contents
in the two decades following his military service in South Africa. A scrapbook collection of poetry by McCarthy and clippings of poetry by others is also included.
Biographical / Historical
Alfred Stephen McCarthy was born September 8, 1878, in Mudgee, New South Wales, Australia. From 1900-1901, he served in South Africa with the 6th Imperial Bushmen of the Imperial Bushmen's Contingent, an Australian cavalry unit. Following this period of service, he returned to New South Wales where he worked as a local police sergeant.
ence in the Boer War and observations of contemporary life in Australia. Aside from the poetry, there is scant evidence of McCarthy's life for the period following his discharge from the police department until his death in 1955.
South African War, 1899-1902 -- Personal narratives; South African War, 1899-1902; McCarthy, Alfred Stephen, 1878-1955
- Inventory, 1877-1955
  - Correspondence
    - [Dumont?] Leo E., 1901 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - McCarthy, Walton (father), 1901 July 18, 1930 November 5 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letters of recommendation
      - McCarthy, Alfred Stephen, 1901, 1921-1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - McCarthy, Frederick and Katie McCarthy, 1932-1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Diary [Boer War service, includes photograph (Alfred S. McCarthy?) and service ribbon (no medal) found in pocket of diary], 1900 April 23-1901 May 30, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Discharge certificates [South Africa Contingent, New South Wales Police Department], 1901 Jul, 1922 November (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Legal documents
    - McCarthy, Alfred Stephen, 1878, 1904, 1910, 1915, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - McCarthy family, 1877, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - New South Wales Police Department [employment records], 1901 October-1922 April (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Photograph [Hester Strijdorn], undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook
    - Poetry by A. S. McCarthy and others, newspaper clippings [glued in ledger], 1936-1941, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Poetry by others and newspaper clippings [loose pages], undated (Box 1, Folder 12)